#	NPC配置表																		
#	Id	Name	PlanetId	Domain	LandingPointId	Course	CourseDescription	Chapter	ChapterDescription	Type	Money	Artifacts	RewardArtifacts	RewardSkill	DialogXML	QuizXML	VlookupNPCId	VlookupLandingPointId	VlookupPlanetId
#	int	string	int	string	int	string	string	string	string	int	int	int[]	int[]	int	int	int	int	int	int
#	配置编号	NPC名字	PlanetId	领域名称	LandingPointId	课程名称	课程描述	章节名称	章节描述	"NPC类型(1-teacher,2-examiner)"	初始金钱	"初始道具(道具ID,数量)"	道具奖励（ID+数量）	技能奖励（ID）	对话文本id	题库文本id	VlookupNPCId	VlookupLandingPointId	VlookupPlanetId
	1101 	Cyra Cloudwell	101 	Cloud Computing	101 	What is cloud computing?	Cloud computing involves much more than off-site servers! Learn different ways that data can be stored and managed with the newest cloud technology.	Introduction		1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	101	1101 	0 	1101 	101 	101 
	1102 	Orion Nimbus	101 	Cloud Computing	101 	What is cloud computing?	Cloud computing involves much more than off-site servers! Learn different ways that data can be stored and managed with the newest cloud technology.	"So, what is cloud computing?"	How it works	1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	102	1102 	0 	1102 	101 	101 
	1103 	Aurora Streamline	101 	Cloud Computing	101 	What is cloud computing?	Cloud computing involves much more than off-site servers! Learn different ways that data can be stored and managed with the newest cloud technology.	Cloud as a service	Three service models	1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	201	1103 	0 	1103 	101 	101 
	1104 	Solara Dataforge	101 	Cloud Computing	101 	What is cloud computing?	Cloud computing involves much more than off-site servers! Learn different ways that data can be stored and managed with the newest cloud technology.	Careers in cloud computing	Infographic	1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	202	1104 	0 	1104 	101 	101 
	1105 	Zephyr Netweaver	101 	Cloud Computing	101 	What is cloud computing?	Cloud computing involves much more than off-site servers! Learn different ways that data can be stored and managed with the newest cloud technology.	Test your knowledge!		2	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	203	0 	1105 	1105 	101 	101 
	1201 	Nova Skylancer	101 	Cloud Computing	102 	How is cloud computing used?	"Cloud offers important benefits for corporations and their customers. Learn practical applications for cloud, and get great tips on a getting started in a cloud career."	Introduction	Cloud at work	1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	301	1201 	0 	1201 	102 	101 
	1202 	Vertex Cloudcaster	101 	Cloud Computing	102 	How is cloud computing used?	"Cloud offers important benefits for corporations and their customers. Learn practical applications for cloud, and get great tips on a getting started in a cloud career."	Cloud helps businesses thrive	Three major values	1	5000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	302	1202 	0 	1202 	102 	101 
	1203 	Luna Byteblade	101 	Cloud Computing	102 	How is cloud computing used?	"Cloud offers important benefits for corporations and their customers. Learn practical applications for cloud, and get great tips on a getting started in a cloud career."	Cloud helps us all	Prepare for mini-quiz	1	1000000	"""3002,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	303	1203 	0 	1203 	102 	101 
	1204 	Aether Skylinker	101 	Cloud Computing	102 	How is cloud computing used?	"Cloud offers important benefits for corporations and their customers. Learn practical applications for cloud, and get great tips on a getting started in a cloud career."	Test your knowledge!		2	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	401	0 	1204 	1204 	102 	101 
	1205 	Zenith Cloudpioneer	101 	Cloud Computing	102 	How is cloud computing used?	"Cloud offers important benefits for corporations and their customers. Learn practical applications for cloud, and get great tips on a getting started in a cloud career."	Cloud computing and you	Explore more	1	1000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	402	1205 	0 	1205 	102 	101 
	1301 	Nimbus Stormrider	101 	Cloud Computing	103 	Journey to Cloud: Envisioning Your Solution	Getting Started with Enterprise Digital Modernization through Cloud Adoption	The New Digital Age	Exploring the concept of digital transformation and its business impact.	1	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	403	1301 	0 	1301 	103 	101 
	1302 	Cirrus Codebinder	101 	Cloud Computing	103 	Journey to Cloud: Envisioning Your Solution	Getting Started with Enterprise Digital Modernization through Cloud Adoption	Benefits of Cloud Computing	An overview of the benefits that cloud computing can provide industries and organizations.	1	1000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	501	1302 	0 	1302 	103 	101 
	1303 	Seraphina Cloudwhisper	101 	Cloud Computing	103 	Journey to Cloud: Envisioning Your Solution	Getting Started with Enterprise Digital Modernization through Cloud Adoption	Cloud Delivery Models	Weighing the benefits and challenges of choosing a cloud delivery model.	1	3000000	"""3003,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	502	1303 	0 	1303 	103 	101 
	1304 	Stratus Techweaver	101 	Cloud Computing	103 	Journey to Cloud: Envisioning Your Solution	Getting Started with Enterprise Digital Modernization through Cloud Adoption	Test your knowledge!		2	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	401	0 	1304 	1304 	103 	101 
	2101 	Ada Synthborn	102 	Artificial Intelligence	201 	AI Foundations	"This lecture introduces you to the Artificial Intelligence landscape. Here we will delve into what is AI, the evolution of AI, and take a brief look at the various technologies that exist today."	Al Impact on the World Today		1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	503	2101 	0 	2101 	201 	102 
	2102 	Turing Cognisphere	102 	Artificial Intelligence	201 	AI Foundations	"This lecture introduces you to the Artificial Intelligence landscape. Here we will delve into what is AI, the evolution of AI, and take a brief look at the various technologies that exist today."	History and Evolution of Al		1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	601	2102 	0 	2102 	201 	102 
	2103 	Neo Neuralink	102 	Artificial Intelligence	201 	AI Foundations	"This lecture introduces you to the Artificial Intelligence landscape. Here we will delve into what is AI, the evolution of AI, and take a brief look at the various technologies that exist today."	AI Explained		1	3000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	602	2103 	0 	2103 	201 	102 
	2104 	Athena Circuitweaver	102 	Artificial Intelligence	201 	AI Foundations	"This lecture introduces you to the Artificial Intelligence landscape. Here we will delve into what is AI, the evolution of AI, and take a brief look at the various technologies that exist today."	AI Technologies		1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	603	2104 	0 	2104 	201 	102 
	2201 	Echo Infobright	102 	Artificial Intelligence	202 	AI Enterprise Applications	"This lecture explores the broad spectrum of how AI is being implemented throughout various industries including automotive, banking, and healthcare."	AI Enterprise Applications		1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	701	0 	0 	2201 	202 	102 
	2202 	Sagan Algorithmforge	102 	Artificial Intelligence	202 	AI Enterprise Applications	"This lecture explores the broad spectrum of how AI is being implemented throughout various industries including automotive, banking, and healthcare."	Natural Language Understanding		1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	702	2202 	0 	2202 	202 	102 
	2203 	Orion Sentience	102 	Artificial Intelligence	202 	AI Enterprise Applications	"This lecture explores the broad spectrum of how AI is being implemented throughout various industries including automotive, banking, and healthcare."	Virtual Agents Overview		1	3000000	"""3009,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	703	2203 	0 	2203 	202 	102 
	2301 	Nova Mindmelder	102 	Artificial Intelligence	203 	Getting Started with Watson Chatbots	"This guide is an instructional approach to working with the IBM Watson™ Assistant service where you can create virtual agents and bots that combine machine learning, natural language understanding, and integrated dialog tools to provide automated customer engagements."	Case Study I		1	1000000	"""3009,2"""	"""1001,20000,1002,6"""	101	2301 	0 	2301 	203 	102 
	2302 	Aria Neuralnova	102 	Artificial Intelligence	203 	Getting Started with Watson Chatbots	"This guide is an instructional approach to working with the IBM Watson™ Assistant service where you can create virtual agents and bots that combine machine learning, natural language understanding, and integrated dialog tools to provide automated customer engagements."	Case Study II		1	2000000	"""3009,3"""	"""1001,20000,1002,7"""	102	2302 	0 	2302 	203 	102 
	2303 	Epsilon Bytebender	102 	Artificial Intelligence	203 	Getting Started with Watson Chatbots	"This guide is an instructional approach to working with the IBM Watson™ Assistant service where you can create virtual agents and bots that combine machine learning, natural language understanding, and integrated dialog tools to provide automated customer engagements."	Case Study III		1	3000000	"""3009,3"""	"""1001,20000,1002,7"""	201	2303 	0 	2303 	203 	102 
	3101 	Sentinel Firewall	103 	Cyber Security	301 	What is cybersecurity?	"You already know ways to protect your devices from hackers. Now learn more about the threats and tactics used by cyberattackers, and dig into concepts like encryption and cryptography."	Introduction		1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	202	3101 	0 	3101 	301 	103 
	3102 	Cipher Lockhart	103 	Cyber Security	301 	What is cybersecurity?	"You already know ways to protect your devices from hackers. Now learn more about the threats and tactics used by cyberattackers, and dig into concepts like encryption and cryptography."	Cybersecurity		1	5000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	203	3102 	0 	3102 	301 	103 
	3103 	Nova Cyberwarden	103 	Cyber Security	301 	What is cybersecurity?	"You already know ways to protect your devices from hackers. Now learn more about the threats and tactics used by cyberattackers, and dig into concepts like encryption and cryptography."	Hackers and cyberattacks		1	6000000	"""3010,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	301	3103 	0 	3103 	301 	103 
	3104 	Astrid Encryptor	103 	Cyber Security	301 	What is cybersecurity?	"You already know ways to protect your devices from hackers. Now learn more about the threats and tactics used by cyberattackers, and dig into concepts like encryption and cryptography."	Cryptography		1	3000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	302	3104 	0 	3104 	301 	103 
	3105 	Orion Vigilance	103 	Cyber Security	301 	What is cybersecurity?	"You already know ways to protect your devices from hackers. Now learn more about the threats and tactics used by cyberattackers, and dig into concepts like encryption and cryptography."	Careers in cybersecurity	Infographic	1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	303	3105 	0 	3105 	301 	103 
	3106 	Seraph Hackscreen	103 	Cyber Security	301 	What is cybersecurity?	"You already know ways to protect your devices from hackers. Now learn more about the threats and tactics used by cyberattackers, and dig into concepts like encryption and cryptography."	Test your knowledge!		2	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	401	0 	3106 	3106 	301 	103 
	3201 	Vanguard Dataward	103 	Cyber Security	302 	Threat Intelligence	"Through this module, you will gain familiarity with the taxonomy of cyberattacks, understand the current impact of cybersecurity threats across different geographies and industries, exploring enterprise security domains."	Reasons Behind Cyber Attacks	"Cyber attackers have an arsenal of sophisticated weapons at their disposal, let's explore the most used ones"	1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	402	3201 	0 	3201 	302 	103 
	3202 	Aegis Shadowcloak	103 	Cyber Security	302 	Threat Intelligence	"Through this module, you will gain familiarity with the taxonomy of cyberattacks, understand the current impact of cybersecurity threats across different geographies and industries, exploring enterprise security domains."	Global Threat Trends	Let's gain a better understanding of the threat landscape understanding attack trends on a global scale.	1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	403	3202 	0 	3202 	302 	103 
	3203 	Aurora Safeguard	103 	Cyber Security	302 	Threat Intelligence	"Through this module, you will gain familiarity with the taxonomy of cyberattacks, understand the current impact of cybersecurity threats across different geographies and industries, exploring enterprise security domains."	Threat Assessment by Industry and Geography	Let's gain a better understanding of the threat landscape by analyzing the attacks in different industries on a global scale.	1	3000000	"""3011,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	501	3203 	0 	3203 	302 	103 
	3204 	Phoenix Cryptotech	103 	Cyber Security	302 	Threat Intelligence	"Through this module, you will gain familiarity with the taxonomy of cyberattacks, understand the current impact of cybersecurity threats across different geographies and industries, exploring enterprise security domains."	Enterprise Security Domains	Let's explore the different cybersecurity domains that need to be addressed within an enterprise.	1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	102	3204 	0 	3204 	302 	103 
	3205 	Zero Darknet	103 	Cyber Security	302 	Threat Intelligence	"Through this module, you will gain familiarity with the taxonomy of cyberattacks, understand the current impact of cybersecurity threats across different geographies and industries, exploring enterprise security domains."	Test your knowledge!		2	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	201	0 	3205 	3205 	302 	103 
	3301 	Nova Firewall	103 	Cyber Security	303 	IBM and Cybersecurity	Get a feel for cybersecurity as a career. You'll see how IBM is helping clients defend against cyberattacks and respond to broader security threats. You’ll also learn about basic cybersecurity terminology and types of cyberattacks.	Introduction		1	3000000	"""3011,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	202	3301 	0 	3301 	303 	103 
	3302 	Echo Codeguard	103 	Cyber Security	303 	IBM and Cybersecurity	Get a feel for cybersecurity as a career. You'll see how IBM is helping clients defend against cyberattacks and respond to broader security threats. You’ll also learn about basic cybersecurity terminology and types of cyberattacks.	What's it like to work at IBM Security?		1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	203	3302 	0 	3302 	303 	103 
	3303 	Sylph Cyberdefender	103 	Cyber Security	303 	IBM and Cybersecurity	Get a feel for cybersecurity as a career. You'll see how IBM is helping clients defend against cyberattacks and respond to broader security threats. You’ll also learn about basic cybersecurity terminology and types of cyberattacks.	To get you thinking ...		1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	301	3303 	0 	3303 	303 	103 
	3304 	Atlas Shieldweaver	103 	Cyber Security	303 	IBM and Cybersecurity	Get a feel for cybersecurity as a career. You'll see how IBM is helping clients defend against cyberattacks and respond to broader security threats. You’ll also learn about basic cybersecurity terminology and types of cyberattacks.	Cybersecurity terminology primer		1	3000000	"""3011,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	302	3304 	0 	3304 	303 	103 
	3305 	Mercury Securelink	103 	Cyber Security	303 	IBM and Cybersecurity	Get a feel for cybersecurity as a career. You'll see how IBM is helping clients defend against cyberattacks and respond to broader security threats. You’ll also learn about basic cybersecurity terminology and types of cyberattacks.	Cyberattack methods		1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	303	3305 	0 	3305 	303 	103 
	3306 	Titan Malwarebane	103 	Cyber Security	303 	IBM and Cybersecurity	Get a feel for cybersecurity as a career. You'll see how IBM is helping clients defend against cyberattacks and respond to broader security threats. You’ll also learn about basic cybersecurity terminology and types of cyberattacks.	Test your knowledge!		2	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	502	0 	3306 	3306 	303 	103 
	4101 	Atlas Datamancer	104 	Data Science	401 	What is data science?	Learn why data science is like hunting for treasure! You'll get a closer look at the work and why you might choose it as your own career.	It’s all about information	Uncovering the story	1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	502	4101 	0 	4101 	401 	104 
	4102 	Aurora Analytix	104 	Data Science	401 	What is data science?	Learn why data science is like hunting for treasure! You'll get a closer look at the work and why you might choose it as your own career.	How do you handle data?	Organizing facts	1	5000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	503	4102 	0 	4102 	401 	104 
	4103 	Nova Insightcaster	104 	Data Science	401 	What is data science?	Learn why data science is like hunting for treasure! You'll get a closer look at the work and why you might choose it as your own career.	How do you become a data scientist?	Building a career	1	6000000	"""3012,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	601	4103 	0 	4103 	401 	104 
	4104 	Orion Statforge	104 	Data Science	401 	What is data science?	Learn why data science is like hunting for treasure! You'll get a closer look at the work and why you might choose it as your own career.	Will you like the work?	Hunting treasure	1	3000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	602	4104 	0 	4104 	401 	104 
	4105 	Seraph Datawhisper	104 	Data Science	401 	What is data science?	Learn why data science is like hunting for treasure! You'll get a closer look at the work and why you might choose it as your own career.	Data science as a career	Infographic	1	4000000	"""3012,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	603	4105 	0 	4105 	401 	104 
	4106 	Aegis Algorithmist	104 	Data Science	401 	What is data science?	Learn why data science is like hunting for treasure! You'll get a closer look at the work and why you might choose it as your own career.	Test your knowledge!		2	3000000	"""3011,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	601	0 	4106 	4106 	401 	104 
	4201 	Quantum Datavault	104 	Data Science	402 	Data Science Landscape	"Understand the evolution and relevance of data science in the world today. Exploring the scientific method for science projects, and the data science team key roles."	The urgency of science	Explore how data scientists use the scientific method to frame their thinking and solve complex problems.	1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	701	4201 	0 	4201 	402 	104 
	4202 	Iris Predictotron	104 	Data Science	402 	Data Science Landscape	"Understand the evolution and relevance of data science in the world today. Exploring the scientific method for science projects, and the data science team key roles."	The‘Data' in Data Science	The explosion of data in the Information Age	1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	702	4202 	0 	4202 	402 	104 
	4203 	Luna Biometrics	104 	Data Science	402 	Data Science Landscape	"Understand the evolution and relevance of data science in the world today. Exploring the scientific method for science projects, and the data science team key roles."	Data science domains	The skills needed to be a data scientist	1	3000000	"""3013,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	703	4203 	0 	4203 	402 	104 
	4204 	Athena Infoguru	104 	Data Science	402 	Data Science Landscape	"Understand the evolution and relevance of data science in the world today. Exploring the scientific method for science projects, and the data science team key roles."	Data science roles	An overview of the key roles within data science	1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	502	4204 	0 	4204 	402 	104 
	4205 	Zenith Experimentor	104 	Data Science	402 	Data Science Landscape	"Understand the evolution and relevance of data science in the world today. Exploring the scientific method for science projects, and the data science team key roles."	Test your knowledge!		2	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	503	0 	4205 	4205 	402 	104 
	4301 	Rhea Patternmaster	104 	Data Science	403 	Data Science on the Cloud	Acquire technical expertise using popular open source data science frameworks including Jupyter notebooks and Python.	The need for cloud-based data science	How cloud can add value to data science teams.	1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	601	4301 	0 	4301 	403 	104 
	4302 	Cipher Dataminer	104 	Data Science	403 	Data Science on the Cloud	Acquire technical expertise using popular open source data science frameworks including Jupyter notebooks and Python.	End-to-end data science with IBM Watson Studio	Introduction to data cleansing tools	1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	602	4302 	0 	4302 	403 	104 
	4303 	Vector Dataharmonizer	104 	Data Science	403 	Data Science on the Cloud	Acquire technical expertise using popular open source data science frameworks including Jupyter notebooks and Python.	Data Science lifecycle: Exploration Phase	Exploring the data journey within the exploration phase of the data science lifecycle	1	3000000	"""3013,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	603	4303 	0 	4303 	403 	104 
	4304 	Eureka Statseeker	104 	Data Science	403 	Data Science on the Cloud	Acquire technical expertise using popular open source data science frameworks including Jupyter notebooks and Python.	Tools to support the Data  Science lifecycle - Production Phase	Exploring the data journey within the production phase of the data science lifecycle	1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	601	4304 	0 	4304 	403 	104 
	4305 	Gemini Modelcrafter	104 	Data Science	403 	Data Science on the Cloud	Acquire technical expertise using popular open source data science frameworks including Jupyter notebooks and Python.	Test your knowledge!		2	2000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	602	0 	4305 	4305 	403 	104 
	5101 	Satoshi Cryptonova	105 	Block Chain	501 	What is blockchain technology?	"Blockchain is a shared, immutable ledger for recording transactions, tracking assets and building trust."	Blockchain fundamentals		1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	102	5101 	0 	5101 	501 	105 
	5102 	Orion Ledgermaster	105 	Block Chain	501 	What is blockchain technology?	"Blockchain is a shared, immutable ledger for recording transactions, tracking assets and building trust."	Blockchain use cases and applications		1	5000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	201	5102 	0 	5102 	501 	105 
	5103 	Nova Chainweaver	105 	Block Chain	501 	What is blockchain technology?	"Blockchain is a shared, immutable ledger for recording transactions, tracking assets and building trust."	Blockchain solutions and resources		1	6000000	"""3014,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	202	5103 	0 	5103 	501 	105 
	5201 	Aria Tokenforge	105 	Block Chain	502 	Introduction to Blockchain Services for Cloud	"Through live-action videos and interactive elements, you will learn about the IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud®. The course begins with an introduction to blockchain technology in general. Next, you will explore a use case for IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud followed by a discussion of basic considerations and deployment steps."	NULL		1	1000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	203	5201 	0 	5201 	502 	105 
	5202 	Atlas Blocksmith	105 	Block Chain	502 	Introduction to Blockchain Services for Cloud	"Through live-action videos and interactive elements, you will learn about the IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud®. The course begins with an introduction to blockchain technology in general. Next, you will explore a use case for IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud followed by a discussion of basic considerations and deployment steps."	NULL		1	2000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	301	5202 	0 	5202 	502 	105 
	5203 	Neo Coinbinder	105 	Block Chain	502 	Introduction to Blockchain Services for Cloud	"Through live-action videos and interactive elements, you will learn about the IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud®. The course begins with an introduction to blockchain technology in general. Next, you will explore a use case for IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud followed by a discussion of basic considerations and deployment steps."	NULL		1	3000000	"""3015,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	302	5203 	0 	5203 	502 	105 
	5204 	Cipher Cryptowisp	105 	Block Chain	502 	Introduction to Blockchain Services for Cloud	"Through live-action videos and interactive elements, you will learn about the IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud®. The course begins with an introduction to blockchain technology in general. Next, you will explore a use case for IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud followed by a discussion of basic considerations and deployment steps."	NULL		1	3000000	"""3015,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	303	5204 	0 	5204 	502 	105 
	5205 	Aurora Datablock	105 	Block Chain	502 	Introduction to Blockchain Services for Cloud	"Through live-action videos and interactive elements, you will learn about the IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud®. The course begins with an introduction to blockchain technology in general. Next, you will explore a use case for IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud followed by a discussion of basic considerations and deployment steps."	NULL		1	3000000	"""3015,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	401	5205 	0 	5205 	502 	105 
	5206 	Phoenix Smartlink	105 	Block Chain	502 	Introduction to Blockchain Services for Cloud	"Through live-action videos and interactive elements, you will learn about the IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud®. The course begins with an introduction to blockchain technology in general. Next, you will explore a use case for IBM Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud followed by a discussion of basic considerations and deployment steps."	NULL		2	3000000	"""3015,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	402	0 	0 	5206 	502 	105 
	6101 	Orion Connectix	106 	Internet Of Things	601 	Introduction to Watson Internet of Things (IoT)	"In this course, you will learn about the Internet of Things (IoT), the key features and capabilities of the platform, and the basic steps to deploy the Watson IoT Platform and IBM Watson Assistant."	NULL		1	4000000	"""1003,10,1004,20"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5"""	403	6101 	0 	6101 	601 	106 
	6102 	Nova Sensora	106 	Internet Of Things	601 	Introduction to Watson Internet of Things (IoT)	"In this course, you will learn about the Internet of Things (IoT), the key features and capabilities of the platform, and the basic steps to deploy the Watson IoT Platform and IBM Watson Assistant."	NULL		1	5000000	"""1101,5,1102,5"""	"""1001,10000,1002,5,1003,30,1004,40"""	501	6102 	0 	6102 	601 	106 
	6103 	Aurora Linknet	106 	Internet Of Things	601 	Introduction to Watson Internet of Things (IoT)	"In this course, you will learn about the Internet of Things (IoT), the key features and capabilities of the platform, and the basic steps to deploy the Watson IoT Platform and IBM Watson Assistant."	NULL		1	6000000	"""3016,1"""	"""1001,20000,1002,5"""	502	6103 	0 	6103 	601 	106 
	6104 	Aria Automator	106 	Internet Of Things	601 	Introduction to Watson Internet of Things (IoT)	"In this course, you will learn about the Internet of Things (IoT), the key features and capabilities of the platform, and the basic steps to deploy the Watson IoT Platform and IBM Watson Assistant."	Test your knowledge!		2	6000000	"""3016,2"""	"""1001,20000,1002,6"""	503	0 	6104 	6104 	601 	106 
