<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Introduction</statement>
			<statement font="1" >In this topic, we will In this topic, we'll explore what digital transformation is, the key transformation drivers, and the technologies at the forefront of enterprise digital transformation.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Throughout this topic, we will attempt to answer the following questions: </statement>
			<statement image="1">1. How have industries benefitted from adopting digital transformation practices?&#xA;2. What role have technologies such as AI, Cloud, and IoT played in the digital revolution?  </statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" color="FF0000">1. How have industries benefitted from adopting digital transformation practices? </statement> 
			<statement font="2">We are at one of the tipping points in history where the impact of technology on business is significant enough to transform the whole way that business gets done. </statement> 
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">The New Digital Age</statement> 
			<statement font="1">It's no secret that the pace of innovation and change has accelerated rapidly over the last few years. From the explosion of social media to online shopping and apps to track your driver, digital transformation has quickly become an integral part of daily life. </statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4">
		<npc>
			<statement>In every industry, business leaders realize customer expectations have created tremendous pressure to change the way they set their strategies and run their organizations. Yet, because they have to manage existing, often traditional, offerings and operations, new requirements to incorporate information and interactivity quickly drive up costs and complexity.</statement>
			<statement>Business leaders have long used information technology (IT) to improve productivity and efficiency, reach new markets and optimize supply chains. What’s new is that customer expectations have also changed. People everywhere are using social networks to find jobs and restaurants, lost friends and new partners—and, as citizens, to achieve common political goals. They are using the internet for entertainment, shopping, socializing, and household management.</statement>
			<statement>At the same time, businesses are undertaking their own digital transformations, rethinking what customers value most, and creating operating models that take advantage of what’s newly possible for competitive differentiation. The challenge for business is how fast and how far to go on the path to digital transformation.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="5" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="5">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" image="3" isBold="true">What is Digital Transformation?</statement>
			<statement >Digital transformation takes a customer-driven, digital-first approach to all aspects of a business, from its business models to customer experiences to processes and operations. It uses AI, automation, hybrid cloud, and other digital technologies to leverage data and drive intelligent workflows, faster and smarter decision-making, and real-time response to market disruptions. And ultimately, it changes customer expectations and creates new business opportunities.</statement>
			<statement>While many organizations have undertaken a digital transformation in response to a single competitive threat or market shift, it has never been about making a one-time fix. According to MIT Sloan Management Review, "Digital Transformation is better thought of as continual adaptation to a constantly changing environment." Its goal is to build a technical and operational foundation, to evolve and respond in the best possible way to unpredictable and ever-changing customer expectations, market conditions, and local or global events. </statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="6" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="6">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Digital Transformation Drivers</statement> 
			<statement>Customer expectations have always been the prime drivers of digital transformation. It began when a rush of new technologies made new kinds of information and capabilities accessible in new ways, such as: </statement>
			<statement>· Mobile devices&#xA;· Social media&#xA;· The internet of things (IoT)&#xA;· Cloud computing</statement>
			<statement isBold="true">Pioneers—disruptors—such as Amazon and Netflix snatched market share from their competition by adopting these technologies to:</statement>
			<statement>· Reinvent business models (e-commerce, electronic delivery).&#xA;· Optimize processes (supply chain management, new feature development).&#xA;· Constantly improve the customer experience (in-context customer reviews, personalized recommendations).</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="7">
		<npc>
			<statement>Competitors adapted to provide even more capability and convenience (or they struggled and maybe even disappeared). Today, customers expect to conduct all business digitally, wherever, and whenever, using any device, with all the supporting information and content they need close at hand. Ultimately, digital transformation is about meeting these ever-escalating expectations. But often, an organization's entry point is a transformation initiative that addresses a specific means to this end, such as:</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="8">Automating business processes</response>
			<response nextnode="9">Defending against disruption</response>			
			<response nextnode="10">Dealing with change effectively</response>
			<response nextnode="11">Enabling on-demand access to more resources, with fewer limits</response>
			<response nextnode="12" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="8">
		<npc>
			<statement>Adding AI and automation serves customers better and produces higher-value work. Theycreate intelligent workflows that simplify operating models, increase productivity and enablemployees to make better decisions faster.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="9">
		<npc>
			<statement>Digital transformation implements technologies and best practices for fast product creation.new customer experiences, and new business models in response to shifts in competitivethreats, market trends, and customer expectations.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="10">
		<npc>
			<statement>This process can include modernizing legacy technology to run on modern infrastructure andinteroperate with modern applications, It builds resilience into systems and processes andassimilates applications and data from acquisitions or mergers.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="11">
		<npc>
			<statement>Digital transformation empowers the business to adopt the widest possible range of solutionsand services from ecosystem partners, industry solution leaders, and multiple cloud serviceproviders.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="12">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true" image="4">COVID-19 pandemic: The ultimate driver? </statement> 
			<statement>In 2020, the COVID-19 pandemic laid bare every organization's digital transformation efforts and progress (or lack thereof). Manufacturers learned just how quickly and effectively they could get new products to market. Retailers scrambled to provide customers with new and safer ways to shop. Employers adopted or expanded technologies that let employees work from home. &#xA;Among operational workflows, supply chains were the most glaringly exposed. Supply chains are always vulnerable; according to the McKinsey Global Institute, supply chain disruptions lasting one month or longer occur every 3.7 years. But shortly after the pandemic began, the United States suddenly imported almost 50% less from major trading partners. Companies were forced to undergo years or decades' worth of supply chain transformation in weeks or months. </statement> 
			<statement>The arrival of the pandemic forced us to reconsider the capabilities we had at our fingertips and adapt them to the circumstances we now face daily. Take video conferencing, for example. We’ve had this capability for years, but we never quite realized its full potential. Now, video calls are an essential part of our day, proving their worth far beyond hosting meetings remotely. &#xA;Patients can have a video consultation with their doctor and have their prescription made available at their closest pharmacy. It benefits the doctor, the patient, and everyone who may come into contact with the patient. This highlights the rapid acceleration of digital transformation out of necessity – but also how the right technology can enhance employee and customer safety.  </statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="13">OK! I have known how industries have benefitted from adopting digital transformation practices.  </response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="13">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" color="FF0000">2. What role have technologies such as AI, Cloud, and IoT played in the digital revolution? </statement> 
			<statement font="2">Enterprises will look back at the start of the 2020s as a moment when they either seized opportunities or naively hoped old ways of doing business would survive. Smarter businesses realize that it's a critical time to meet people's evolving needs and give their customers exceptional experiences. Business transformation is the key to accomplishing these goals, studies show. </statement> 
			<statement font="1">As disruption and volatility may continue for the foreseeable future, the organizations that apply human-focused strategies Business transformation will determine who thrives in the new landscape ahead and the new capabilities of emerging and advancing technologies will be positioned to lead in the “new normal” to come. </statement> 
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Transformational Technologies</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>

		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="14">
		<npc>
			<statement>Virtually any digital technology can play a role in an organization's digital transformation strategy. But technologies that figure to play a central role today and in the near future include:  </statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="15">Digitization</response>
			<response nextnode="16">Artificial intelligence and automation</response>
			<response nextnode="17">Cloud Computing</response>
			<response nextnode="18">Microservices</response>
v			<response nextnode="19">Internet of Things</response>
			<response nextnode="20">Blockchain</response>
			<response nextnode="21" isShown="false">Continue</response>

		</player>
	</node>


	<node id="15">
		<npc>
			<statement>Digitization, or digitalization, is the conversion of paper-based information into digital data.Digitizing printed information may seem like an old practice, but it's a component of digitaltransformation efforts in virtually every industry or sector, It's also a cornerstone of foundationatransformation initiatives in healthcare (electronic medical records or EMR), government, andeducation.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="16">
		<npc>
			<statement>Artificial intelligence (AI) technologies, such as machine learning, enable a computer ormachine to mimic the human mind's capabilities. AI learns from examples, recognizing objectsmaking decisions, and more. When combined with automation, AI can infuse intelligence andreal-time decision-making into any workflow, It can drive everything from innovative smartproducts, from increasingly personalized customer and user experiences to optimizedworkflows for supply chain management, change management, and more.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="17">
		<npc>
			<statement>Cloud computing is on-demand access, via the internet, to computing resources-applications.servers (physical servers and virtual servers), data storage, development tools, networkingcapabilities, and more-hosted at a remote data center managed by a cloud services provider</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="18">
		<npc>
			<statement>Whether they're accessing a website or a mobile app, people have high expectations of the appsthat they regularly use. As a result, companies must continuously deliver new features and fixesIn the past, this process was painful because an application was usually developed, built, andmade available as a single, often monolithic, application, Microservices is an applicationarchitectural stvle in which an application is composed of many discrete, network-connectedcomponents.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="19">
		<npc>
			<statement>The Internet of Things (IoT) refers to objects and devices equipped with sensors that collect andtransmit data over the internet, IoT devices are where digital technology meets physical reality.Applications like supply chain logistics and self-driving cars generate real-time data that AI andbig data analytics applications turn into automation and decisions.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="20">
		<npc>
			<statement>Blockchain is a distributed, permanent and unchangeable ledger or record of electronictransactions or assets. Blockchain provides total transaction transparency to those who requireit and is inaccessible to those that don't, Organizations are using blockchain as a foundation forsuper-resilient supply chain and cross-porder financial services transformations.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="21">
		<npc>
			<statement>Combining multiple technologies, including cloud, cognitive AI, mobile, and the Internet of Things (IoT), Digital Reinvention rethink customer and partner relationships from a need-, use- or aspiration-first perspective. Digital Reinvention helps organizations create unique, compelling experiences for their customers, partners, employees, and other stakeholders. These benefits arise regardless of whether enablement or fulfillment of the experience involves the direct provision of products or services or orchestration of products or services from partner organizations by way of a business ecosystem. The most successful digitally reinvented businesses establish a platform of engagement for their customers, acting as an enabler, conduit, and partner. </statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="22" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="22">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">How Cloud Fits into the Bigger Picture  </statement> 
			<statement>The ongoing digital revolution affects individuals and businesses alike. Increasingly, social networks and digital devices are the default means for engaging government, businesses, and civil society, as well as friends and family members. People use mobile, interactive tools to determine who to trust, where to go, and what to buy. This means that the last best experience that people have anywhere becomes the minimum expectation for the experience they want everywhere, including in the enterprise. Given the competitive landscape, this means that enterprises must undertake their own digital transformations, rethink what their customers value most, and create operating models that take advantage of what is newly possible for competitive differentiation. The challenge for the enterprise is how fast and how far to go down the path to digital transformation and cloud adoption.</statement> 
			<statement image="5">Increasing customer expectations and a more competitive business context have placed tremendous pressure on business leaders to change the way they set their strategies and run their organizations. New requirements to incorporate more information and greater interactivity quickly drive up costs and complexity.</statement> 
			<statement>Business leaders have long used information technology to improve productivity and efficiency, reach new markets, and optimize supply chains. What is new is that customer expectations have changed.</statement> 
			<statement>· How can enterprises best respond to this shift? &#xA;· How can they take advantage of the opportunity to innovate and grow through technology adoption? &#xA;· How can they do all this cost-efficiently?</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="23" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="23">
		<npc>
			<statement>This is the domain of digital transformation and its intersection with cloud adoption. Digital transformation incorporates the change associated with the application of digital technology in all aspects of society. Cloud Adoption is the way in which businesses implement digital transformation.&#xA;We believe the most crucial decision that a company can make to successfully pursue a digital transformation strategy is to wholeheartedly yet thoughtfully adopt the cloud as the IT platform of choice. We have observed many companies that have successfully used cloud adoption to rapidly advance their digital transformation strategy. We have also seen companies make unsuccessful cloud adoption decisions that have hampered or set back their pace of digital transformation. What we will show you in this book is how to model your decision-making process after the successful transformations while avoiding the common pitfalls we’ve seen in the unsuccessful transformations. &#xA;In our work with clients, we have found that enterprises that can develop and effectively execute a digital transformation strategy and take full advantage of new technologies, such as cloud are able to transform their business models and set a new direction for entire industries.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="24" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="24">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true" video="1">How the hybrid cloud can create the world's computer</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="25" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="25">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Digital Transformation in Action</statement> 
			<statement image="6">Convoy looks to disrupt the USD $700billion trucking industry Convoy, a Seattle-based start-up, has developed an Uber-like app interface to give individual truckers a more efficient way to connect with individuals and businesses that want to ship goods. &#xA;By matching truck drivers with clients directly, Convoy disintermediates traditional brokers. The company and other entrants such as Los Angeles-based Cargomatic intend to reduce the average transportation prices and delivery times while increasing average loads and trucker income.&#xA; Lending Club challenges traditional banks in their backyard San Francisco-headquartered Lending Club offers better borrowing and lending rates than traditional banks. </statement> 
			<statement image="7">Operating online, Lending Club automates peer-to-peer loans across its digital platform. With operating costs that are 60 percent lower than those of traditional banks, Lending Club has experienced massive growth over the past five years. Lending Club still has substantial space for growth in an area of the market that has historically produced more than 4 billion in profits annually. </statement> 
			<statement image="8">Clean Energy Collective devises new modes of generation and consumption Founded in 2010, the Colorado-based Clean Energy Collective (CEC) builds, operates, and maintains community-based clean energy facilities.&#xA;Using remote metering technologies that integrate seamlessly with utility billing systems and installing solar panels either on customer’s property or elsewhere, CEC is able to track and apply for clean energy production credits directly on customer’s bills. &#xA;By the end of 2015, more than 27 gigawatts of solar capacity was online in the United States, enough to power more than 5.4 million homes. </statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="26" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="26">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Why it matters? </statement> 
			<statement>Since the rise of the internet in the late 1990s, companies under increasing pressure to stay ahead of the curve. Social media, big data, artificial intelligence, and cloud computing are just a few of the technologies at the forefront of the digital revolution. To remain competitive, organizations must continually adapt and innovate in order to meet customer expectations.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="end">Thank you for your teaching.</response>
		</player>
	</node>
</dialogue>
