<quiz boss="true">
 <question type="MCS" timelimit="30">
     <statement>Choose the correct sequence of the following blockchain network types to its description.
Network Types: Private, Permissioned, Public, Consortium.
1. One organization governs the network;
2. Anyone can join and participate in the network;
3. Participation in network and certain transactions is restrictive;
4. Multiple organizations share the blockchain maintenance responsibilities.
     </statement>
   <analysis></analysis>
   <options>
     <option id="A">1, 3, 2, 4</option>
     <option id="B">1, 3, 4, 2</option>
     <option id="C">1, 2, 4, 3</option>
     <option id="D">1, 2, 3, 4</option>
   </options>
   <analysis></analysis>
   <answers>
     <answer>A</answer>
   </answers>
 </question>
    
  <question type="MCS" timelimit="30">
    <statement>Bitcoin and Blockchain are the same technology.</statement>
    <analysis></analysis>
    <options>
      <option id="A">True</option>
      <option id="B">False</option>
    </options>
    <analysis></analysis>
    <answers>
      <answer>B</answer>
    </answers>
  </question>

  <question type="MCS" timelimit="30">
    <statement>How is trust established in a blockchain network?</statement>
    <hint></hint>
    <options>
      <option id="A">Data is decentralized and stored on multiple computers to discourage tampering.</option>
      <option id="B">Data storage is based on the written ledger system that has been in use for centuries.</option>
      <option id="C">Data storage locations do not synchronize, thus reducing the threat of security violations.</option>
    </options>
    <analysis></analysis>
    <answers>
      <answer>A</answer>
    </answers>
  </question>

  
  <question type="MCS" timelimit="30">
    <statement>Ordering Services uses the Raft protocol. Click the statement that most accurately describes the Raft protocol.</statement>
    <hint></hint>
    <options>
      <option id="A">The system can withstand the loss of nodes as long as one leader node remains and is active.</option>
      <option id="B">The system can withstand the loss of nodes as long as a majority of ordering nodes remain.</option>
      <option id="C">The system cannot withstand the loss of the leader node, but it can withstand the loss of follower nodes.</option>
    </options>
    <analysis></analysis>
    <answers>
      <answer>B</answer>
    </answers>
  </question>

    
  <question type="MCS" timelimit="30">
    <statement>Where would your peer be deployed if your Kubernetes cluster is located in Denver, your main office is in Philadelphia, and your linked console is in Seattle?</statement>
    <hint></hint>
    <options>
      <option id="A">Denver</option>
      <option id="B">Philadelphia</option>
      <option id="C">Seattle</option>
    </options>
    <analysis></analysis>
    <answers>
      <answer>A</answer>
    </answers>
  </question>
</quiz>
