<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Cloud computing—at your service!</statement>
			<statement>Any traditional service can be delivered through the cloud. This concept is called anything as a service, or XaaS.</statement>
			<statement image="1">Let’s compare the three most popular service models of cloud computing: software as a service (SaaS), platform as a service (PaaS), and infrastructure as a service (IaaS). Here’s a diagram that shows you the kinds of tools and data that fit into each model.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
		<npc>
			<statement>Click each section to learn more about the three service models.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3">Software as a service (SaaS)</response>
			<response nextnode="4">Platform as a service (PaaS)</response>
			<response nextnode="5">Infrastructure as a service (IaaS)</response>
			<response nextnode="6" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3">
		<npc>
			<statement>With SaaS, software and data both reside online. Users can log in on a browser from almost any kind of device on almost any operating system, enter what they need, and out pops their result. Since their organization doesn’t need special software to use SaaS, it doesn’t have to buy applications. Instead it pays for yearly or per-user subscriptions to the service.
You can visualize SaaS as someone else's kitchen. You go online and place your order. They provide the recipe, cook the food, and deliver it to you.
When you hear SaaS, think of uses like email or online shopping.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4">
		<npc>
			<statement>With PaaS, a vendor provides only the platform—meaning the infrastructure, operating systems, storage, and much of the code. The user’s organization manages the application’s resources and the data. (For more on the infrastructure, refer to the next section.)
You can visualize PaaS as someone else’s kitchen. But you provide the raw food and the recipe, and you do the cooking.
When you hear PaaS, think of containers, databases, runtime, and integration.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="5">
		<npc>
			<statement>Companies turn to IaaS when they want to build their own applications from the ground up, or move existing applications from a data center into the organization to cut down on IT costs. With IaaS, a vendor provides the infrastructure and architecture like hardware, software, servers, and storage, and also handles expensive support systems like backup, security, and maintenance. This leaves the organization’s computing architecture on the web so that teams in different locations can work together, while keeping application development inside the company’s own online structure.
You can think of IaaS as your own kitchen, where you provide the recipe and do the cooking. But someone else maintains your appliances and manages your utilities.
When you hear IaaS, think of computing, storage, and networking resources.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3">
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">But here’s a question for you to think about ...</statement> 
			<statement>But here’s a question for you to think about ...</statement>
			<statement  video="2" image="1">Keep your best guess in mind as you continue reading. You’ll find the answer a couple of topics from now, and it might surprise you!</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
		</player>
	</node>
</dialogue>
