<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">The Client: NYC Restaurant and Bakery chain.</statement>
            <statement image = "1">One of the clients of Global Law Firm LLC is a large Restaurant company with base of operations in
Manhattan, NYC
Intent - they are looking to provide a personalized experience, and increased client engagement on the wake of COVID-19.
Approach - Increase capabilities of their online channels to ensure touchless interactions on reservations and orders, using conversation agents.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
		<npc>
            <statement>- Adam works with Ana from the client's team; they have a first virtual meeting where he lays down the foundation of AI ethics.
Then, they go over the recently approved Ethical Guide: Advanced Conversation Agents
- Adam encourages Ana to work with her Designers and Domain experts to put a plan in place before starting to work on the Virtual Agent, including a strong focus on aligning the intent of the client to avoid known-pitfalls.</statement>
            <statement image = "2"/>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3">
		<npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">The Guide: Building a conversational agent</statement>
			<statement image = "3"/>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4">
		<npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">How does a bot interpret conversation?</statement>
            <statement>A bot interprets our conversation digitally by identifying the intents and entities in our utterances, which in turn will give it the information it needs to craft a proper response.</statement>
            <statement image = "4"/>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="5" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="5">
        <npc>
            <statement image = "5-1">-Alia recommends IBM Watson Assistant as the tool to use for this task
- Watson Assistant is made for conversation builders, not coders
- Includes intuitive dialog builder and content library.</statement>
            <statement image = "5-2"/>
        </npc>
        <player>
            <response nextnode="6" isShown="false">Continue</response>
        </player>
	</node>

	<node id="6">
        <npc>
            <statement image = "6-1">Follow now Adam as he builds his first virtual agent with the help of Alia:
• Create Watson Assistant Service
• Create an assistant
• Create a dialog skill
• Add intents from a content catalog
• Build a Dialog
• Add Your Skill to Your Assistant
• Integrate the Assistants</statement>
            <statement image = "6-2"/>
        </npc>
        <player>
            <response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
        </player>
    </node>
    
</dialogue>
