<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">What’s the path into this field?</statement>
			<statement>In an earlier topic, you saw young professionals talk about data science. Did you notice that no one got into this field the same way? That’s because data science is an emerging study that hasn’t been defined clearly until recently. (And, in some areas, the definition is still changing.)</statement>
			<statement>It helps to think of data science as creating knowledge from data, no matter what technique is used to analyze the data. It’s like a treasure hunt. You start with raw text, or numbers, or graphics, or any other kind of data, and you explore that data to discover valuable patterns and insights.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>No special certification or skillset qualifies you as a data scientist. You just start analyzing data in any of its many forms. If you use scientific techniques to derive information from data, you’re a data scientist, no matter how you entered the field! But there are areas of study that can help you prepare to hunt for data treasure, and we’ll look at them later in this course.</statement>		
			<statement video="1">In the next video, you’ll learn how different paths can lead you to this career destination.</statement>	
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>This table organizes customer information from the hardware store by characteristics such as customer number or name. Each row shows information related to a particular customer, while each column shows one customer characteristic that spans a group of customers.</statement>		
			<statement>As you can see, structured data tends to be well-organized, making it easier for data scientists to discover its treasure using common data analysis tools. Spreadsheets are based on tables like this, so they handle structured data very well.</statement>	
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>Then there’s unstructured data, which is a fancy way of saying “everything else.” We use this term when there's no built-in organization (or structure) to the data. Unstructured data can be a collection of audio files, or social media posts, or essay texts, or even song lyrics.</statement>		
			<statement>Here are two examples to help you see the difference:</statement>	
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="5" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="5"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>1.Your Department of Motor Vehicles takes photographs of everyone who gets a driver’s license. A collection of those images is unstructured data. (But the table of peoples’ names, addresses, and licence numbers that indexes those photos is structured data.)&#xA;2.A downloadable library might offer text from thousands of different books. The catalog listing names, authors and dates of those books is structured data. (But the text of those books is unstructured data.)</statement>		
			<statement>Unstructured data can be harder to work with than structured data, but it’s still useful! Suppose a video game company is getting a lot of email bug reports about a new release. The text of those emails is unstructured data. By examining those texts (and perhaps by converting some of their contents to structured data), a data scientist can figure out patterns and identify the problem so the company can fix it!</statement>	
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
		</player>
	</node>
</dialogue>
