<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Introduction</statement>
			<statement>In this topic, we'll explore the unique roles of the data analyst, data scientist, and data engineer. </statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Throughout this topic, we will attempt to answer the following questions:</statement> 
			<statement>1.How is a Data Science team structured? &#xA;2.What are the primary role and responsibilities of the data analyst?&#xA;3.What are the primary role and responsibilities of the data scientist?&#xA;4.What are the primary role and responsibilities of the data engineer?&#xA;5.How do other supporting roles add value to the data science team? </statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3">
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true" color="FCFF1A">1. How is a Data Science team structured?</statement> 
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">In practice, several people work on a team to build data products. Your analyses will only be as good as the team that is responsible for collecting, building, and analyzing the underlying data. </statement>
			<statement font="2">Data Science isn’t just about frameworks, data sources, and pipelines—it’s also about people. Enterprises embarking on a Data Science journey have a much greater opportunity for success when they have executive leadership support and the right talent in key Data Science roles.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Data science is a team sport.</statement> 
			<statement image="1">The greatest challenge of the big data revolution is making sense of all the information generated by today’s vast digital economy. It’s well enough for an organization to collect every slice of data it can reach, but how does it extract value from this massive volume of information?</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="5" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="5">
		<npc>
			<statement>The more data you have, the better the quality of your reports and strategic recommendations, right? Sure...if you can analyze that data intelligently and quickly and make it actionable with valuable insights. Otherwise, more data can mean more problems: messy data, storage woes, security risks, frustrated business teams, and overloaded IT staff. So how do you figure out what you really want from your data—and which data can get you those answers? How do you turn raw metrics and records into information that has (and drives) actual business value? Do you have the skills your business needs to drive results? Successful organizations build data science teams that incorporate different skill sets and responsibilities instead of relying on a few elite individuals.</statement> 
			<statement>In practice, several people work on a team to build data products. Your analyses will only be as good as the team that is responsible for collecting, building, and analyzing the underlying data.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="6" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="6">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">What does the data science team bring to the table?</statement> 
			<statement>The deeper programming types, such as data engineers and front-end developers, bring consumability to data science. The mathematics and data scientist types use statistical algorithms to find patterns in data. Throughout the process, everything needs to align with the preferred business outcome, which is guided by the eye of the business analyst. Working together, the data science team can outthink today’s challenges and problems to create new opportunities and possibilities for tomorrow. Which talents and abilities define the members of a data science team, and how do they complement each other?</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="7">
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true" color="FCFF1A">2. What are the primary role and responsibilities of the data analyst? </statement> 
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Data Analytics involves finding the right data in these data systems, cleaning it for the purposes of the required analysis, and mining data to create reports and visualizations. </statement>
			<statement font="2">Good Data Analysts select and address the business problems that have the most value to the organization. Armed with data and analytical results, they must present their informed conclusions and recommendations to technical and non-technical stakeholders.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="8" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="8">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Who is a Data Analyst？</statement> 
			<statement>To be a Data Analyst, you need to be in constant communication with the business users. </statement> 
			<statement isBold="true">Line of business users</statement>
			<statement>This encompasses all users that consume the output of data science analytics, for example, business analysts analyzing dashboards to monitor the health of a business or the end-user using an application that provides a recommendation as to what to buy next.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="9" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="9">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Characteristics</statement> 
			<statement>· Great communicator and presentation skills&#xA;· Critical thinking and agile design&#xA;· Familiar with visualization tools </statement> 
			<statement isBold="true">Role</statement>
			<statement>· Domain exploration and understanding&#xA;· Collect and analyze data&#xA;· Understand data&#xA;· Explain and visualize results&#xA;· Communicate with stakeholders</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="10" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="10">
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true" color="FCFF1A">3. What are the primary role and responsibilities of the data scientist? </statement> 
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Data Scientists take Data Analytics even further by performing deeper analysis on the data and developing predictive models to solve more complex data problems.</statement>
			<statement font="2">Solving problems and answering questions through data analysis is quickly becoming the norm in today’s data-driven world. As real-world experiments become ubiquitous in modern business, the data scientist is evolving into the role that stokes, tweaks, and fuels this operational engine.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="11" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="11">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Who is a Data Scientist?</statement> 
			<statement>Data scientists are often referred to as “unicorns” because they have a rare combination of talents: they handle a variety of responsibilities and skill sets covering mathematics, statistics, domain expertise, communications, and more.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="12" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="12">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Characteristics</statement> 
			<statement>· Is eternally curious - What? Why? How?&#xA;· Research mindset&#xA;· Versed in statistics and math&#xA;· Constantly being in the “know”</statement> 
			<statement isBold="true">Role</statement>
			<statement>· Collect and analyze data&#xA;· Extract insights from patterns using machine learning models&#xA;· Explain and visualize results</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="13" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="13">
		<npc>
			<statement>Basically, the job of the data scientist is to look for hidden patterns. They accomplish this by applying advanced analytics techniques, including (but not limited to) machine learning, modeling, statistics, and visualization. Often, data scientists will construct models to predict outcomes or discover underlying patterns; their game plan is to produce actionable insights that can be used to improve future outcomes.A good data scientist will not just address business problems; he or she will zero in on the problems that have the most value to the organization.</statement> 
			<statement>Because data scientists are involved in each step of the journey in building data products, they tend to bring a holistic view to solving problems with data. However, they can’t be experts in everything—this is where their team can help. They experiment continuously by deploying new predictive models, business rules, and orchestration logic into next-best-action-powered applications.</statement>
			<statement>A skilled data scientist explores and examines data from multiple disparate sources. They will pore through all incoming data with the goal of linking new information to historical data to find a relationship or trend that offers a crucial competitive advantage or addresses a pressing business problem. They don’t just collect and report on data; they look at it from many angles, determine what it means, and then recommend ways to apply the findings. They need to make sure their queries are correct and must be able to back up their conclusions with sound models and trusted data—as the data scientist is often expected to present recommendations to management and executive teams.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="14" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="14">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Top skills for data scientists</statement> 
			<statement>Data scientists are distinguished by their strong business acumen, plus the ability to communicate findings to both business and IT leaders in a way that can influence how an organization approaches a business challenge. The data scientist often becomes the liaison between the IT department and C-level executives. Therefore, he or she must be able to speak both “languages” and understand the hierarchy of data—they can’t just be a data expert. This also means data scientists must have a solid understanding of the business as well as the conviction to stand behind their findings in the face of opposition.</statement>
			<statement>Data scientists are inquisitive and curious: exploring, asking questions, doing what-if analyses, and questioning existing assumptions and processes. A data scientist’s technical skills often include multiple programming languages, familiarity with big data management and analysis tools like Apache Hadoop and Spark, and experience with tools that help them visualize data and insights.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="15" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="15">
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true" color="FCFF1A">4. What are the primary role and responsibilities of the data engineer? </statement> 
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Data Engineering entails managing data throughout its lifecycle and includes the tasks of designing, building, and maintaining data infrastructures. </statement>
			<statement font="2">These data infrastructures can include databases – relational and NoSQL, Big Data repositories and processing engines – such as Hadoop and Spark, as well as data pipelines – for transforming and moving data between these data platforms.</statement>	
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="11" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="16">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Who is a Data Engineer?</statement> 
			<statement>The data scientist may be responsible for uncovering hidden patterns in data, but where do you think they get their data, and what happens when their solutions need to scale to thousands of users or handle sensitive information? Data scientists can only go so far without proper support to operationalize their work.</statement> 
			<statement>Enter the data engineer. At a high level, data engineers help gather, organize and clean the data that data scientists will ultimately use to build their analysis. If data scientists extract value from data, data engineers make sure data flows smoothly from source to destination so it can be processed.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="17" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="17">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Characteristics</statement> 
			<statement>· Tech savvy&#xA;· Programming skills (Python, Golang, Java, etc.)&#xA;· Can perform math and statistics operations&#xA;· Frequently uses Machine Learning API calls&#xA;· Familiar with infrastructure architecture </statement> 
			<statement isBold="true">Role</statement>
			<statement>· Familiar with infrastructure architecture &#xA;· Utilizes advanced programming techniques&#xA;· Test and deploy Machine Learning models&#xA;· Manages the data infrastructure</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="18" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="18">
		<npc>
			<statement>Data engineers are responsible for setting up systems and processes that other data workers—including data scientists—use and rely on to work with data. Data engineers must understand how to finesse the flow of data to minimize movement latencies and bring agility to analytics. They also work with front-end developers when moving data science projects into production. In many organizations, a data engineer will oversee integrating data, including designing, building, and measuring data ingestion and integration pipelines for large volumes of temporal data from different sources. Examples include database extracts, application server logs, scanned images, voice recordings, Twitter streams, websites, and health sensor data. Once continuous pipelines are installed—to and from these huge “pools” of filtered information—data scientists can pull relevant data sets for their analyses.</statement> 
			<statement>Data engineers are often tasked with laying the groundwork for a data analyst or data scientist to easily retrieve the data needed for their evaluations and experiments.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="19" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="19">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Top skills for data engineers</statement>
			<statement>Data engineers are hard-core engineers who understand the internal workings of database software. They compile and install database systems, write complex queries, scale them to multiple machines, manage backups and deploy disaster recovery systems. They develop, construct, test, and maintain architectures such as databases and large-scale data processing systems.</statement> 
			<statement>Good data engineers are always learning and thinking about which new technologies will help them drive the business forward. This prompts them to develop a deep programming background, as well as cultivate familiarity with Hadoop-based technologies such as MapReduce, Hive, and Pig. Data engineers usually have significant experience with SQL-based technologies and NoSQL technologies, as well as data warehousing methodologies and solutions such as extract, transform, load (ETL).</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="20" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="20">
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true" color="FCFF1A">5. How do other supporting roles add value to the data science team? </statement> 
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Data Science isn’t just about frameworks, data sources, and pipelines—it’s also about people. Enterprises embarking on a Data Science journey have a much greater opportunity for success when they have executive leadership support and the right talent in key Data Science roles.</statement>
			<statement font="2">Here are suggestions from IBM concerning who should be on a Data Science team. Our experience suggests that these specific roles should be filled to get buy-in on the project and create a successful solution.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="21" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="21">
		<npc>
			<statement font="1" isBold="true">Team behind Data Science</statement>
			<statement image="2">Here are suggestions from IBM concerning who should be on a Data Science team. Our experience suggests that these specific roles should be filled to get buy-in on the project and create a successful solution.</statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="22" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>
	
	<node id="22">
		<npc>
			<statement isBold="true">Data science team support</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="22.1">PRODUCT OWNER</response>
			<response nextnode="22.1">DEVELOPER</response>
			<response nextnode="22.1">THE BUSINESS ANALYST</response>
			<response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="22.1">
		<npc>
			<statement>The Product Owner providing business guidance, user research support, and serving as a consultant in terms of understanding the business need of the company in relation to the Data Science project in scope. </statement> 
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="22" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="22.2">
		<npc>
			<statement>Although developers don’t always have a fully dedicated position within a data science team, they are an essential piece of the puzzle. A successful project usually productizes the data science work so it can serve an internal stakeholder or external customer. Baking data science into business processes is how companies build competitive advantage through data.</statement> 
			<statement>Developers often come in at the end of the data science workflow. They are responsible for building the applications where the models will sit—applications that leverage the insights and data gathered from the rest of the data science team. This requires a fair amount of programming time, and it can be a challenging job. Lack of integrated technologies can stifle developers’ progress, making it difficult to embed the data science team’s analysis.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="22" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="22.3">
		<npc>
			<statement>The Business Analyst — sometimes is referred to as the citizen analyst — provides business-level expertise and guidance to the data science teams. Their responsibility is to apply domain knowledge and make data-informed decisions.</statement> 
			<statement>The business analyst understands what the business needs but doesn’t have the technical background to develop a detailed analysis. Improvements in technology and a deeper understanding of the user profile have turned them into “analytical consumers,” allowing them to make decisions based on data insights. Flexible and user-friendly technologies allow them to develop some business-level analysis without coding and without having to ask the data scientist. This gives business analysts more independence, increasing the chance they will use the data science team’s findings in their everyday analyses.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="22" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>
</dialogue>
