<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">What is a database?</statement>
			<statement image="1">Almost every data scientist will spend time working in a database, which is an organized collection of structured data in a computer system. (Remember, structured data is usually organized in a table format with rows and columns, like the following example.)</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>Most databases today are organized as relational databases, which are collections of multiple data sets or tables that link together. For example, one table might list names and addresses, while the other might list properties and their owners. If some of the owners also appear in the name-and-address table, the two tables can be linked, creating a relational database. Relational Database Management Systems (RDMSs) help data scientists correlate information from all the tables within the database, change related data, or add and delete data in the database without breaking its structure.</statement>		
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Use a database to store and sort data</statement>
			<statement>Most database management systems use some form of Structured Query Language, or SQL, to ask questions or “query” the database or to modify its contents. SQL is incredibly useful, and it’s something you can learn through a book, an online course, or a computer club. Let’s see how it works.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4"> 
		<npc>
			<statement image="2">Suppose you have a million rows of data in a table of registered voters in your state. (Many databases are this big, or even larger!) The table contains information about each voter’s polling place, party affiliation, and age. If you wanted to just get the information for all the voters under the age of 21, you could write a query in SQL instead that performs a simple search. That would look like this:</statement>
			<statement>Yes, a simple search might have answered this particular question. However, if you want to uncover voters who live in a particular geographic area so you can study how frequently people of different ages in that group show up at the polls, your query will overwhelm a simple search. But SQL can do the job!</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="5" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="5"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>While SQL is the underlying language that drives most work done in relational databases, there are many RDBMSs in which you can do that work. As you venture into this field, you’ll run into names like these:</statement>
			<statement>· MySQL&#xA;· Microsoft Access&#xA;· PostgreSQL&#xA;· Oracle&#xA;· IBM DB2&#xA;· MongoDB</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="6" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="6"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Choose the right tools to manage data</statement>
			<statement>Where do you begin? There are dozens of useful data science tools and platforms! Here’s a list of some popular and open source platforms that you can use to begin your own data science journey.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="7"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>Click the following sections to learn more about tools to manage data.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7.1">R is a good place to start</response>
			<response nextnode="7.2">Python works for general purposes</response>
			<response nextnode="7.3">MATLAB helps crunch numbers</response>
			<response nextnode="7.4">Apache Spark supports big data and machine learning</response>
			<response nextnode="8" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="7.1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>R is a programming language and free software environment often used for statistical analysis and data science. Many would-be data scientists start with this tool or with one of the popular R interfaces, and there are hundreds of useful packages in R that help with data visualization such as ggplot2.</statement>
			<statement image="3">Here’s what RStudio looks like. It’s a popular interface for working in R.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="7.2"> 
		<npc>
			<statement>Python is a popular, general-purpose programming language that can also be used for data science. Pair it with a library like pandas library and with a useful interface, and Python can help you create new insights and data visualizations.</statement>
			<statement image="4">Here’s what Python looks like in a notebook interface.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="7.3"> 
		<npc>
			<statement image="5">MATLAB was built to focus on numerical computing. It is often used in higher education.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="7.4"> 
		<npc>
			<statement image="6"></statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="7" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="8"> 
		<npc>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
		</player>
	</node>
</dialogue>
