<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> <!-- 6 Videos Here Lack-->
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Blockchain use cases and applications</statement>
            <statement>BTracing fresh seafood from the moment it’s caught:
IBM Food Trust is helping Raw Seafoods increase trust across the food supply chain by tracing every catch right from the water — all the way to supermarkets and restaurants.</statement>
            <statement>Improving cryptocurrency security in financial services:
INBLOCK issues Metacoin cryptocurrency, which is based on Hyperledger Fabric, to help make digital asset transactions faster, more convenient and safer.</statement>
            <statement>Transforming healthcare outcomes with blockchain:
The IBM Blockchain Platform can change the way your ecosystem ensures trust, data provenance and efficiency to improve patient care and profitability.</statement>
            <statement>Fresh thinking in blockchain, AI and IoT for supply chain:
Learn how Golden State Foods is using the immutability of blockchain to trace goods through its supply chain and help ensure food quality.</statement>
            <statement>Fueling innovation in the oil and gas industry:
Vertrax and Chateau Software launched the first multicloud blockchain solution built on IBM Blockchain Platform to help prevent supply chain disruptions in bulk oil and gas distribution.</statement>
            <statement>Increasing trust in retailer-supplier relationships:
The Home Depot is using IBM Blockchain to gain shared and trusted information on shipped and received goods, reducing vendor disputes and accelerating dispute resolution.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">Blockchain for industries</statement>
            <statement>Industry leaders are using IBM Blockchain to remove friction, build trust and unlock new value. Select your segment to see how.</statement>
            <statement>
1. Supply chain
2. Healthcare
3. Government
4. Retail
5. Media and advertising
6. Oil and gas
7. Telecommunications
8. Manufacturing
9. Insurance
10. Financial services
11. Travel and transportation</statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
        </player>
    </node>
    
</dialogue>
