<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">Blockchain overview</statement>
            <statement>Blockchain technology is an immutable shared ledger that facilitates the process of recording transactions and tracking assets in a business network. You can track and trade anything of value. Blockchain is cost-effective and secure.  </statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">Business case for blockchain</statement>
            <statement image = "2">Blockchain resolves transaction systems limitations, including the following:
1. Cash is useful only in local transactions.
2. Third-party validation increases transaction overhead.
3. Fraud, cyber attacks, and mistakes add to the cost and complexity of doing business, and expose network participants to risk if a system is compromised.
4. People without access to banks require parallel payment systems. </statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">Key features of a blockchain</statement>
            <statement image = "3-1">Distributed ledger technology:
All network participants have access to the distributed ledger and its immutable record of transactions.
With this shared ledger, transactions are recorded only once, eliminating the duplication of effort that is typical of traditional business networks.</statement>
            <statement image = "3-2">Records are immutable:
No participant can change or tamper with a transaction after it’s been recorded to the shared ledger. If a transaction record includes an error, a new transaction must be added to reverse the error, and both transactions are then visible.</statement>
            <statement image = "3-3">Smart contracts:
To speed transactions, a set of rules – called a smart contract – is stored on the blockchain and executed automatically. </statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">Types of blockchain networks</statement>
            <statement>There are four types of blockchain network - Public, private, permissioned, or consortium.</statement>
            <statement image = "4-1">Public blockchain networks:
A public blockchain is one that anyone can join and participate in, such as Bitcoin.
Drawbacks might include substantial computational power required, little or no privacy for transactions, and weak security. These are important considerations for enterprise use cases of blockchain.</statement>
            <statement image = "4-2">Private blockchain networks:
A private blockchain network, similar to a public blockchain network, is a decentralized peer-to-peer network, with the significant difference that one organization governs the network. That organization controls who is allowed to participate in the network, execute a consensus protocol and maintain the shared ledger. Depending on the use case, this can significantly boost trust and confidence between participants. A private blockchain can be run behind a corporate firewall and hosted on-premises.</statement>
            <statement image = "4-3">Permissioned blockchain networks:
Businesses configuring a private blockchain will generally configure a permissioned blockchain network. It is important to note that public blockchain networks can also be a permissioned. This places restrictions on who is allowed to participate in the network, and in which transactions. Participants need to obtain an invitation or permission to join.</statement>
            <statement image = "4-4">Consortium blockchains:
Multiple organizations share the responsibilities of maintaining a blockchain. These pre-selected organizations determine who may submit transactions or access the data. A consortium blockchain is ideal for business when all participants need to be permissioned and have a shared responsibility for the blockchain.</statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="5" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="5"> <!--2 VIDEOS HERE LACK-->
        <npc>
            <statement></statement>
            <statement>One of the concepts in the previous video is that a blockchain network is a secure digital ledger system. The following video elaborates on the shared ledger.</statement>
        </npc>
        <player>
           <response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
        </player>
    </node>
    
</dialogue>
