<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="2" isBold="true">IBM Blockchain Platform elements</statement>
            <statement font="1" >IBM® Blockchain Platform for IBM Cloud includes the IBM Blockchain Platform Console (UI), a Hyperledger Fabric, and IBM VS Code extension. </statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
        <npc>
            <statement image = "2"></statement>
            <statement>IBM Blockchain Platform Console (UI):
This is the console that allows you to create and manage your blockchain components.
After you provision a service instance in IBM Cloud™', you can deploy an instance of the IBM Blockchain console and link it to your Kubernetes cluster on IBM Cloud™.
Then you can use the console to create and manage your blockchain components in your Kubernetes cluster. There is no charge for the console.</statement>
            <statement>Hyperledger Fabric Components
The console is used to create and manage blockchain components that are based on Hyperledger Fabric v1.4.7 and v2.x - Certificate Authority, peer, and ordering service images.
These components are deployed into your Kubernetes cluster and storage is provisioned for them using the default storage class when they are deployed.
Additional components that are not shown here include applications, smart contracts, and channels.</statement>
            <statement>IBM VS Code Extension (Development Tools)
Download the VS Code extension from the VS Code marketplace in order to get started with developing, packaging, and testing client applications and smart contracts.</statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3"><!--1 Video Lack Here-->
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">IBM Blockchain Platform components</statement>
            <statement></statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="4">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">Example blockchain network</statement>
            <statement image = "4"/>
            <statement>Org A
Org A can access only Channel X.
It has its own Certificate Authority that is responsible for distributing cryptographic identity material.</statement>
            <statement>Channel X
Channel X (in gold) includes all four organizations.</statement>
            <statement>Org B
Org B can access only Channel X.
It has its own Certificate Authority that is responsible for distributing cryptographic identity material.</statement>
            <statement>Channel Y
Channel Y (in red) is restricted to Org C and Org D.</statement>
            <statement>Ordering Service
The ordering service consists of five Raft nodes that defines policies and network participants.</statement>
            <statement>Org C
Org C can access both Channel X and Channel Y.
It has its own Certificate Authority that is responsible for distributing cryptographic identity material.</statement>
            <statement>Org D
Org D can access both Channel X and Channel Y.
It has its own Certificate Authority that is responsible for distributing cryptographic identity material.</statement>
        </npc>
        <player>
           <response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
        </player>
    </node>
    
</dialogue>
