<dialogue>
	<node id="1"> 
		<npc>
			<statement font="3" isBold="true">Tutorial: Deploy the Watson IoT Platform and IBM Watson Assistant</statement>
            <statement font="2" isBold="true">Getting Started</statement>
            <statement>In this tutorial, you will perform the basic steps to deploy the Watson IoT Platform and IBM Watson Assistant.</statement>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">IMPORTANT:</statement>
            <statement>This IBM Cloud documentation collection pertains to the IBM Watson IoT Platform Lite pricing plan and includes basic getting started information, API references, and general troubleshooting information. For the full Watson IoT Platform feature documentation, see the Watson IoT Platform product documentation on IBM Documentation. More information about the various plans can be found in Watson IoT Platform service plans.</statement>
		</npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="2" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="2">
        <npc>
            <statement font="2" isBold="true">About This Task</statement>
            <statement>Before you can begin receiving data from your IoT devices, you must connect them to Watson IoT Platform. Connecting a device to Watson IoT Platform involves registering the device with Watson IoT Platform and then using the registration information to configure the device to connect to Watson IoT Platform.</statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
			<response nextnode="3" isShown="false">Continue</response>
		</player>
	</node>

	<node id="3">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">Before You Begin:</statement>
            <statement>Before you can start using Watson IoT Platform, you must have the following items:
1. An IBM Cloud account.
2. A Watson IoT Platform instance. You can create a Watson IoT Platform instance directly from the Watson IoT Platform page in the IBM Cloud Services Catalog.
3. A device that meets the following requirements:
a.Your device must be able to communicate by using HTTP or MQTT protocols.
b.The device messages must conform to the Watson IoT Platform message payload requirements.
For more information, see Developing devices on Watson IoT Platform.
Explore the following options depending on your situation:</statement>
            <statement image = "3"></statement>
        </npc>
		<player>
            <response nextnode="4" isShown="false">Continue</response>
        </player>
    </node>

    <node id="4">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">Quick Tip</statement>
            <statement>Registering a device involves classifying the device as a device type, giving the device a name, and providing device information. Then you provide a connection token or accept a token that is generated by Watson IoT Platform.
You can register your devices one at a time from the Watson IoT Platform dashboard, or you can use the Watson IoT Platform API to add multiple devices. </statement>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">To Add a Device from the Watson IoT Platform Dashboard:</statement>
            <statement>1. In the IBM Cloud console, click Launch on the Watson IoT Platform service details page.
The Watson IoT Platform web console opens in a new browser tab at the following URL (where org_id is the ID of your Watson IoT Platform organization):
https://org_id.internetofthings.ibmcloud.com/dashboard/#/overview
2. In the Overview dashboard, from the menu pane, click Devices and then click Add Device.
3. Create a device type for the device that you are adding. Each device that is connected to the Watson IoT Platform must be associated with a device type. Device types are groups of devices that share common characteristics.
A. Click Create device type.
B. Enter a device name, such as my_device_type, and a description for the device type.
NOTE:
The device type name must be no more than 36 characters and can contain only alphanumeric characters (a-z, A-Z, 0-9) and any of the following characters: _, ., and -.
C. Optional: Enter device type attributes and metadata.
You can add and edit attributes and metadata later.
4. Click Next to begin the process of adding your device with the selected device type.
5. Enter a device ID, for example my_first_device.
The device ID is used to identify the device in the Watson IoT Platform dashboard and is also a required parameter for connecting your device to Watson IoT Platform.
The device type name must be no more than 36 characters and can contain only alphanumeric characters (a-z, A-Z, 0-9) and any of the following characters: _, ., and -.
For network connected devices, the device ID could be the device MAC address without any separating colons.
6. Click Next to complete the process.
7. Provide an authentication token or accept an automatically generated token. If you choose to create your own token, make sure that it is between 8 and 36 characters long and consists only of alphanumeric characters and the following characters: _, ., !, &, @, ?, \*, +, (, ), and -.
The token must not contain repeated character sequences, dictionary words, user names, or other predefined sequences.
8. Verify the summary information is correct and then click Add to add the connection.
9. In the device information page, copy and save the following details:
- Organization ID
- Device type
- Device ID
- Authentication method
- Authentication token
You'll need the organization ID, device type, device ID, and authentication token to configure your device to connect to Watson IoT Platform.
After you register a device with Watson IoT Platform, you can use the registration information to connect the device and start receiving device data.
Connection recipes are available for some commonly used devices at Device connection recipes on IBM.com.</statement>
        </npc>
        <player>
            <response nextnode="5" isShown="false">Continue</response>
        </player>
    </node>
    
    <node id="5">
        <npc>
            <statement font="1" isBold="true">To Connect a Device to Watson IoT Platform:</statement>
            <statement>1. Set up your device for MQTT messaging and authenticate by using the organization ID, device type, device ID, and authentication token.
2. Send device messages to your Watson IoT Platform organization by using the MQTT protocol. The following information is required when connecting your device:
- URL: org_id.messaging.internetofthings.ibmcloud.com (where org_id is the ID of your Watson IoT Platform organization).
- Port:
1883 (disabled by default)
8883 (encrypted)
443 (websockets)
- Device ID: _orgid:_devicetype:_deviceid
- User name: use-token-auth
- Password: Authentication token
- Event topic format: iot-2/evt/_eventid/fmt/_formatstring (where _eventid specifies the event name that's shown in Watson IoT Platform, and _formatstring is the format of the event, such as JSON).
- Message format: JSON
- Example payload: { "d": {"key1": "value1"} }
For more information, see MQTT connectivity for devices.</statement>
            <statement image = "3"></statement>
        </npc>
        <player>
            <response nextnode="6" isShown="false">Continue</response>
        </player>
    </node>
    
    <node id="6">
        <npc>
            <statement font="2" isBold="true">What's Next</statement>
            <statement>Extend the data analytics features by creating and connecting your own apps to consume device data.
Check out the client libraries for tools to build code for integrating and connecting your devices and apps.
Explore the Watson IoT Platform API Documentation.
Connect an IBM® Cloudant® for IBM Cloud service to your Watson IoT Platform to store historical device data.
To take advantage of the full Watson IoT Platform feature set, you can purchase one of the Connection and Analytics Service plans and then migrate your existing environment.
To migrate plans, contact your IBM® representative or raise a support ticket.
A more detailed set of getting-started guides and sample applications that step through the basics of developing a ready-for-production, end-to-end IoT prototype system with Watson IoT Platform are also available in the Watson IoT Platform product documentation on IBM Documentation. If you are a developer who is new to working with Watson IoT Platform, use the step-by-step processes in the Getting Started guides section.</statement>
        </npc>
        <player>
            <response nextnode="end">Thank you.</response>
        </player>
    </node>

</dialogue>
